[Subtitles by danielsangeo]
Okay, new job:
Find something to climb out of here.
I'm doing a lot of jobs.
Every employer I've had pulls this crap.
They hire me to do one thing,
but what they really mean is one
thing plus fifty other things
because they don't have enough people.
And, guess what?  I'm the new hire.
So, I do it.
Forever.
[lock buzzes]
Right...
Well, at least Black Mesa
has a legitimate excuse
that most of their workforce is dead.
Gotta cover for the dead guys.
Now, what's this say?
"Superbus Via..."
I don't know much Latin.
Language of science, my ass.
It would be kind of cool if I wrote
out "Latin is a dead language" in blood
and made it look like one of the
soldiers did it as his dying action.
People would say, "Wow, those were
his last words, huh?" Make them think.
Hm. I guess I could stack these bodies
to make a human staircase out of here.
But, that's going to be a lot of hauling.
I'd probably need at least five or six.
They're heavy, too.
I'd wear myself out
if I moved all of them.
I'm sure there's a cheap lab
stool around here somewhere.
[explosion-like sound]
What was that?
I don't like hearing explosions
if I'm not the one
[door hisses]
making--
God, Jesus...!
Frickin' door conspiracy!
You can't tell me there isn't one.
They know...
Hey, a button!
I've got my button-pressing
gloves on and I'll--wait...
Wait... wait....
Maybe I shouldn't press THIS button.
I'm getting some weird vibes here.
Like, why is there a dead guy
inside these cages?
I don't know what department
this is, but this isn't how we kept our lab.
If someone turned up dead in one of our
experiments, it got cleaned up immediately.
I'm not going to press that
button.
I'm going to press THIS bu--
no, maybe I shouldn't.
I'm having déjà vu.
I've been in this room before.
The last time I pressed that
button, I remember a white hot light
and then the universe felt just
a little bit emptier.
We shouldn't be making these buttons.
Whoa-ho-ho-ho!
It's that time of the year again.
Okay...
TAG!  YOU'RE IT!
HECU: We've got Freeman!
NOT YOU, THE OTHER GUY!
YOU'RE IT!  YOU'RE IT!  YOU'RE IT!
RRRRR!
No tag-backs.
[hic]
Oh, nice.  I have the hiccups.
Man, I get really nervous
after killing people.
Is that normal?
I think it's because there
could be other people to kill
and I never really know if my job's done.
[hic]
[alien grunt growls]
CLEARLY IT ISN'T!
THAT'S A PRETTY BIG
OVERSIGHT IF I'M TRYING--
WHY IS IT MY JOB TO KILL
EVERYONE?!
I almost feel like my degree
is being wasted here.
I mean, what I'm doing now
really has nothing to do with
quantum mechanics or general relativity.
There's just no crossover.
Don't come near me!
No!  NO!
I HAVE A PERSONAL SPACE ZONE, GOD DAMMIT!
PERSONAL SPACE!
[hic]
Nobody has any respect for my privacy!
They all think I've done something!
[gibbering]
Out of ammo, okay!
Sorry!  Sorry about that!
Thought you were somebody else.
Did he buy that?
[gibbering]
I would--I don't...I don't know.
Maybe he respects my privacy.
I mean, there is no
actual RIGHT to privacy,
but it's implied by the rest of
the Constitution... and this gun.
What's going on here?
[lock buzzes]
It's a prototype
cheese slicer, I guess.
Doesn't look like it's going too well.
Okay, where is this guy?
I can't have somebody sneakier
than I am running around here.
Then the whole system falls apart.
Oh, I think I got him.
Yeah, that's right.
[hic]
Thought you could take cover in this
completely empty hallway with nothing in it.
And the door opens so that means
you weren't trying to run away.
So, that really was your plan.
Well, you're not going to make
sergeant like that.
So, looks like I've
gone in circles again.
But now, I can do it on the next floor!
I can't wait; I'm going to run up there.
[gunfire in distance]
[hic]
OKAY, I NEED EVERYBODY TO CALM DOWN!
JUST CALM DOWN!
I CAN'T HELP ANYONE IF YOU'RE NOT CALM!
ARE WE CALM YET?!
YES?!
NO?!
OH-OH MY GOD!
WE NEED TO RELAX!
YOU'RE NOT RELAXED!
JESUS CHRIST!
Aaaahhh....
This session's off to a rocky start, but
I think I just need to change tactics.
OKAY, LISTEN UP EVERYBODY!
ARE WE CALM?!
RELAX AND FOLLOW THE SOUND OF MY VOICE!
I NEED YOU TO TAKE DEEP BREATHS!
DEEP BREATHS!
YES, THAT'S GOOD!
NO!  NOT LIKE THAT!  START OVER!
[hic]
Actually, I think that's all the
time we have for today.
We'll meet again next week.
Okay, now that everyone's calmed
down, we can start thinking rationally.
It stands to reason that
with so many of you here,
there must be a functional entrance.
[hic]
Unless I'm imagining everyone here.
That would be a game changer.
Hey...
[laser blasts, whines]
Whoa!
That's awesome.
I'm going to leave this on.
It looks expensive.
Hm, that is something to think about.
If I am imagining all these soldiers,
then I'm just shooting random people.
Or maybe nobody at all.
But, if that's the case,
then it make sense why--
[hic]
--people are trying to kill me.
[houndeyes squeal, charge up]
Dammit, not you!
You're not even people!
Wuaaah!
Bouncing nightmares...
[hic]
[houndeyes charge up]
IF I WANT YOU LITTLE SPACE MAGGOTS
JUMPING AT MY FACE, I'LL ASK FOR IT!
AND I'M NEVER GOING TO ASK FOR THAT!
[laser blasts, whines]
Well, lasers make me happy.
Maybe not as much food,
some painkillers,
bed rest,
not being persecuted,
just getting my life
back on track in general.
But, hey, I'll take lasers.
GUARD: What is this thing?
Some-some kind of weapon?
SCIENTIST: Put that down. It's a prototype.
I'm hearing voices again.
[tau cannon blast]
What?
GUARD: Why aren't we using it?
SCIENTIST: It's much too unpredictable.
SCIENTIST: Don't let it overcharge!
GUARD: What-what do you mean, "Over--"
[tau cannon explosion]
[gasps]
You know, for every mistake I make,
somebody else is making an even bigger one.
Yuck. Well, I'm not touching that thing.
I doubt it's any safer
with blood all over it.
[laser blast, whines]
Hey, how did those guys get in here?
Oh, of course.  Through the ceiling.
I guess they blew up--
[hic]
--the rope they used to get in there.
I guess I'm getting jaded in that
seeing some body parts lying around
doesn't freak me out the way it used to.
It still freaks out most people.
A lot.
Like, if we're able to cl--
oh, hey, a button!
[button clicks]
[growls]
Damn, I don't think it has any power.
But, yeah, if we were able to
clone body parts easily,
I'd just want to sprinkle them
across the countryside
and covertly videotape people
discovering them.
Small towns where not a lot
happens would be best.
Just leave--
[hic]
Just leave a severed arm
lying there on Main Street.
Especially if they don't know it's cloned.
Wait, I've already been here.
Christ...
So, then a week later, I'd come back and
leave a cloned leg there that's just as fresh
so that they think I'm hacking
up some guy in my basement.
People would worry over nothing.
It'd be great.
[laser blast, whines]
More lasers.  Fuck yeah!
Maybe if I turn all these on and redirect them,
I could start shooting down the satellites.
That would be so rad.
Oooh!  I can feel the hum off this thing!
Let's try again!
[machine powering up]
Oh-ho-ho!
[high pitched whine]
Bad ass!
Oh yeah!
Once I reorient this thing, I
can shoot a satellite down for sure.
[doors open, computer chirps]
Somebody's going to be missing
their TV channels tonight.
[hic]